Audiovisual Collection RRFA.02 RRFA.02.TEST2
RRF Test Repository
Audiovisual Collection 2019TEST
1916 - 2012 (bulk 1963 - 2005)
RRF Test Repository
RRFA.02.TEST2
53 Cubic Feet
1054 Video Recordings 716 analog video recordings; 338 digital objects
71 Sound Recordings
89+ Motion Picture Films
Robert Rauschenberg, an American artist, worked in a wide range of subjects, styles, materials, and techniques and has been called a forerunner of essentially every postwar movement since Abstract Expressionism. He remained, however, independent of any particular affiliation. Active from the late-1940s to 2008, his practice embodied lifelong commitment to collaboration and he worked performers, printmakers, engineers, writers, artists, and artisans from around the world.
Materials in the Audiovisual Collection document Rauschenberg and his artistic pursuits, including footage and news coverage of artworks, exhibitions and performances. Recordings relating to the artist's personal life and interests, including his social and political involvement, are also present.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into eight series: 1. Artists, Organizations and People; 2. Artwork; 3. Exhibitions and Projects; 4. Found Footage; 5. Off-Air Broadcast Recordings; 6. Performance; 7. Personal and Biographical; Series 8. Unidentified; and Series 9. Separated Housings.
Restriction
As of March 2016, only digital surrogates are available for access. All other items are restricted. Please contact the Archives for more information.
Scope and Content Note
Materials in the Audiovisual Collection document Rauschenberg's artistic pursuits and personal activities as well as his associations with other artists, arts professionals, and arts organizations. The collection includes footage of Rauschenberg creating artworks, installations and openings of his exhibitions, and performances in which he participated or contributed design elements. Many of Rauschenberg's projects, exhibitions, and performances are also documented in contemporaneous news coverage, interviews with curators, and full-length documentary works. Biographical materials in the collection feature recordings such as artist statements and biographical pieces created by the artist, lectures and symposia covering a range of social and arts-related topics in which he participated, and testimonies given before the U.S. Congress. Personal and collected recordings such as home movies, industrial and education films, and off-air recordings of television broadcasts are also present.
The collection is comprised of seven hundred sixteen analog video recordings on a variety of formats, over eighty-nine films, seventy-one sound recordings and three hundred thirty-eight digital objects. Items that have Foundation assigned registration numbers are indicated in the finding aid.
As of March 2016, only digital objects (digital videos and digital surrogates of analog videos) are available for viewing and access. Digital objects are also indicated in the finding aid.
Bibliography
Robert Rauschenberg: A Retrospective, edited by Susan Davidson and Walter Hopps, pp. 206–23. Exh. cat. New York: Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1997.
Art, Modern.; Modern dance.; Performance art.
- Artwork, 1966 - 2012; 1.2 Cubic Feet; 44 Video Recordings 32 analog video recordings; 12 digital videos and surrogates; 1 Sound Recordings
  Scope and Content Note
  Series 2. Artwork documents Rauschenberg's artworks and his art practices. Highlights include the artist's film work "Canoe" and the sound track to "The ¼ Mile or 2 Furlong." Documentary recordings include footage of art making, installations and restoration, maintenance instructions, and news coverage relating to particular works and series. The series is comprised of thirty-two analog video recordings, three 16 mm films, one sound recording, and twelve digital videos and surrogates.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by artwork title. Cross-references are provided for agents and subjects which appear elsewhere in the archives.
  - General
    - "Permanence of Art Materials." NBC: Nightline., 1985 August 9; Rivers, Larry, 1925-2002; 0.09 Cubic Feet; 3 Video Recordings interfiled footage log duplicates of broadcast video recording (Box 8, Object 22, Reg number 95.V004.00, Object 23, Reg number 95.V004.01, Box 37, Object 29, Reg number 95.V004.02)
      Rivers, Larry, 1925-2002
  - "Canoe" (1966)
    - Exhibition copies, 1966; 0.07 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings exhibition duplication master and viewing copy (Box 8, Object 24, Reg number 66.V001.05, Box 57, Object 1, Reg number 66.V001.01)
    - Film transfer master, 1966; 0.05 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings analog film transfer master and digital surrogate; B&W; 00:05:00 (Box 37, Object 3, Reg number 66.V001.03)
    - Viewing copies, 1966; 0.06 Cubic Feet; 3 Video Recordings access copies; 00:05:04 (Box 8, Object 25, Reg number 66.V001.00, Object 26, Reg number 66.V001.02, Object 27, Reg number 66.V001.04)
  - "The 1/4 Mile or 2 Furlong Piece" (1981–1998)
    - Sound track, 1997; 0.002 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings emergency backup copy of installation sound track; 01:00:14 (Box 30, Object 7, Reg number 87.A001.00)
  - Documentation
    - "7 Characters" series (1982)
      - Working segment, circa 1982; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings analog working segment and digital surrogate; 00:30:48 (Box 8, Object 28, Reg number 85.V094.00)
    - "A Quake in Paradise (Labyrinth)" (1994)
      - Installation, Captiva, 1995; 0.005 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings analog raw footage and digital surrogate; 00:10:54 (Box 30, Object 8, Reg number 95.V008.00)
    - "Art Car-BMW" (1986)
      - "BMW Art Cars." CNN-NY, 1986 November 9; 0.05 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings duplicate of broadcast videorecording and digital surrogate; 00:02:24 (Box 37, Object 30, Reg number 89.V024.00)
    - "Bicycloid VI" (1993)
      - Tokyo Urban Renewal Public Art Project, circa 1994; Kitagawa, Furamu, 1946-; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings duplicate (Box 8, Object 31)
        Kitagawa, Furamu, 1946-
    - "Dry Cell" (1953)
      - Restoration, 1996 December; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings raw footage (Box 8, Object 32, Reg number 96.V003.00)
    - "Eco-Echo" series (1992–1993)
      - "Saff Tech Arts." CBS Sunday Morning., 1993 January 31; Saff, Donald, 1937-; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings duplicate of broadcast video recording and digital surrogate; 00:09:57 (Box 8, Object 33)
        Saff, Donald, 1937-
    - Glass tires
      - Casting, 1995, undated; 0.04 Cubic Feet; 3 Video Recordings raw footage; 2 analog video recordings and 1 digital surrogate; 00:32:55 (Box 8, Object 1, Object 2, Reg number 95.V006.00)
      - Urban Glass, 1995; 0.005 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings raw footage (Box 30, Object 9, Reg number 95.V007.00)
    - "Immerse" (1994)
      - RR with painting, 1994, 1999; 0.01 Cubic Feet; 3 Video Recordings raw footage; 2 analog video recordings and 1 digital surrogate; 00:41:14 (Box 30, Object 10, Reg number 94.V002.00, Object 11)
    - "Japanese Clayworks" (1982/1985) and "Japanese Recreational Clayworks" (1982–1983/1985/1989)
      - [Otsuka Omi Ceramics Co.], NHK footage and segments, 1982; 0.09 Cubic Feet; 3 Video Recordings raw and edited footage shot for news segments (Box 8, Object 3, Reg number 210.V005.01, Object 4, Reg number 86.V010.00; 86.V023.00, Box 37, Object 27)
    - "Monogram" (1955-1959)
      - "The Goat." Xmas Files. Charlotte Street Productions., 1995 December 13; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings duplicate of broadcast video recording; NTSC; stereo (Box 8, Object 5)
    - "Mud Muse" (1968-1971)
      - "Mud Muse", circa 1971; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate; 00:00:17
        General Note
        Database records show that this footage may be from 1971 at Moderna Museet, Stockholm.
    - "Oracle" (1962-1965)
      - "Description, Maintenance and Test Video Tape", 1998; 0.08 Cubic Feet; 4 Video Recordings duplicate video recordings to accompany to "Operations and Maintenance Manual"; NTSC (Box 8, Object 6, Reg number 98.V007.02, Object 7, Reg number 98.V007.00, Object 8, Object 9)
      - Installation views at multiple exhibitions, circa 1997-1998; 1 Video Recordings digital excerpt compilation of multiple exhibitions; 00:27:50
      - "Oracle Redesigned", 1997 March - December; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings (Box 8, Object 10, Reg number 98.V007.00; 98.V007.02)
      - Sound recordings, undated; 0.01 Cubic Feet; 2 Sound Recordings Polyester audio tape; 7.5 ips; 1x mono; 1x stereo 1/4 in. (Box 35, Object 17, Reg number 75.A006.01, Object 18, Reg number 75.A006.02)
    - Original art for Man of the Year TIME magazine (1985)
      - "Man of the Year." Time CBC., 1985 December 30; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings duplicate of edit from broadcast video recording (Box 8, Object 11)
    - "Rebus" (1955)
      - Rebus in Philadelphia, circa 1975; 0.005 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings polyester audio tape; 7.5 ips; mono 1/4 inch (Box 35, Object 19, Reg number 75.A008.00)
    - "Revolver" series (1967)
      - Silkscreening, circa 1967; 0.25 Cubic Feet; 3 Motion Picture Films color; positive; no sound 16 mm; 2 Video Recordings 2 digital betacam transfers (Box 39, Object 1, Reg number 67.MM001.01, Object 2, Reg number 67.MM001.02, Box 8, Object 15, Object 16)
        Marden, Brice, 1938-
    - "Study for Chinese Summerhall" portfolio (1983)
      - Signing prints at Graphicstudio, 1983 January 22; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings raw footage (Box 8, Object 12, Reg number 83.V013)
    - "Untitled (Cardboard)" (1972)
      - Making "Untitled (Cardboard)" at 381 Lafayette, 1972; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate of film original; color; silent; 00:03:05
    - Various
      - "Robert Rauschenberg: Cardboards and Gluts." Heinrich Schmidt. Vernissage TV., 2012 May; Davidson, Susan, 1958-; White, David; 1 Video Recordings digital video recording; 00:06:26
        Davidson, Susan, 1958-; White, David
- Performance, 1954 - 2009; 8.45 Cubic Feet; 149 Video Recordings 90 analog video recordings; 59 digital surrogates; 29 Motion Picture Films; 12 Sound Recordings
  Series 6. Performance contains materials relating to performances that Rauschenberg choreographed, performed in or created set pieces and media works for as well as documentation regarding choreographers with whom he collaborated. The recordings include footage and sound recordings of performances and rehearsals, excerpt compilations and documentaries, and original film and sound works created for performance pieces. Highlights include 16 mm films of Rauschenberg's "Linoleum" as well as masters and source materials for "Elastic Carrier" made for Trisha Brown's "Set and Reset." The series is comprised of ninety analog video recordings, twenty-nine 16 mm films, twelve sound recordings, and fifty-nine digital surrogates.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by personal name of the choreographer or by the name of the event. Cross-references are provided for agents and subjects which appear elsewhere in the archives.
  - 9 Evenings
    - Event footage, Schilling, Alfons, 1934-
      - Backstage and excerpts, 1966; Klüver, Billy, 1927-2004; 0.04 Cubic Feet; 4 Video Recordings 2 analog film transfer duplicates and 2 digital surrogates; silent; 00:29:04; 00:28:18 (Box 8, Object 4, Reg number 66.V017.00, Object 5)
        Klüver, Billy, 1927-2004
      - Corrected RR selection, undated; 0.05 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings film transfer excerpts (Box 37, Object 1)
    - "9 evenings." Alfons Schilling., 1966; Schilling, Alfons, 1934-
      - Film transfers, circa 1966; 0.04 Cubic Feet; 3 Video Recordings 2 analog [film transfer] duplicates and 1 digital surrogate; 00:33:45 (Box 8, Object 6, Reg number 66.V012.00, Object 7, Reg number 66.V016.00)
      - 16 mm prints and excerpts, 1966; 0.13 Cubic Feet; 2 Motion Picture Films B&W; positive; 1 optical sound track, 1 silent 16 mm (Box 44, Object 3, Reg number 66.MM002.01, Reg number 66.MM002.00)
    - "9 Evenings: Theater and Engineering, October 13-23, 1966, Excerpts from the 10 Performances", 2009; Martin, Julie; Klüver, Billy, 1927-2004; Schilling, Alfons, 1934-
      - MiniDV camera footage, undated; 0.002 Cubic Feet; 13 Video Recordings 1 videocassette and 12 digital surrogates (Box 32, Object 24)
      - Full film, 2009; 0.001 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings full feature (Box 30, Object 26)
  - Brown, Trisha, Brown, Trisha, 1936-
    - General
      - Trisha Brown Dance Company audiocassette, undated; 0.01 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings (Box 32, Object 27)
      - Trisha Brown Dance Company promotional tape, 1988 July 13; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings promotional copy (Box 8, Object 8)
    - "Accumulation with Talking plus Watermotor for Stephen"
      - Wide and close camera angles, 1996 April 9; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings analog video recording and digital surrogate; 00:25:38 (Box 8, Object 9, Reg number 78.V001.00)
    - "Astral Converted (50")"
      - Premiere at the National Gallery of Art concurrent with "Rauschenberg Overseas Cultural Interchange", 1991 May 14; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings raw footage (Box 8, Object 10, Reg number 91.V038.00)
    - "Astral Convertible"
      - "Aeros", 1990; Barr, Burt; 0.07 Cubic Feet; 3 Video Recordings 2 analog video recordings and 1 digital surrogate; 00:50:48 (Box 37, Object 2, Reg number 91.V039.00, Box 8, Object 12)
      - Prototype show review, 2004 October; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings (Box 8, Object 11, Reg number 204.V008.00)
    - "Dancing on the Edge"
      - WGBH New Television Workshop, circa 1980; 0.07 Cubic Feet; 4 Video Recordings 2 duplicates of broadcast video recording and 2 digital surrogates; 00:28:39; 00:28:58 (Box 37, Object 3, Box 8, Object 13, Reg number 80.V004.00)
    - "For MG: The Movie"
      - Backstage, circa 1991; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings duplicate; B&W (Box 8, Object 14)
    - "Set and Reset"
      - "Elastic Carrier"
        - 16 mm masters, circa 1983; 1.54 Cubic Feet; 6 Motion Picture Films interfiled time code sheets and instructions B&W; positive; silent 16 mm; 6 Sound Recordings B&W; positive; optical sound track 16 mm; 8 Sound Recordings full coat magnetic sound track 16 mm (Box 42, Object 4, Reg number 83.MM001.01, Object 5, Reg number 83.MM001.02, Object 6, Reg number 83.MM001.03, Object 7, Reg number 83.MM001.04, Object 8, Reg number 83.MM001.05, Box 43, Object 1, Reg number 83.MM001.06, Object 2, Object 3, Box 51, Reg number 83.A001.01, Reg number 83.A001.02, Reg number 83.A001.03, Reg number 83.A001.04, Reg number 83.A001.05, Reg number 83.A001.06, Reg number 83.A001.07, Reg number 83.A001.08)
        - Film transfers, 1983; 0.49 Cubic Feet; 20 Video Recordings 15 analog film transfers and 5 digital surrogates (Box 8, Object 15, Object 16, Reg number 83.V002.02, Object 17, Reg number 83.V002.03, Object 18, Object 19, Object 20, Reg number 83.V002.06, Object 21, Reg number 83.V002.01, Object 22, Object 23, Object 24, Reg number 83.V002.04, Box 37, Object 1, Object 2, Object 3, Object 4, Object 5, Reg number 83.V010.00)
        - Source material, undated; 0.12 Cubic Feet; 2 Motion Picture Films found footage 16 mm (Box 52, Object 2, Object 3)
      - WGBH Television, 1984; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings duplicate of broadcast video recording (Box 8, Object 25, Reg number 84.V003.00)
    - Compilation
      - "Dancing on the Edge," "Set and Reset," "Accumulation with Talking", 1988 October 20; 0.04 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings interfiled footage log Secacam submaster and NTSC duplicate of broadcast video recording (Box 8, Object 26, Reg number 88.V048.00, Object 27, Reg number 88.V048.01)
  - Cunningham, Merce
    - General
      - "498 3rd Ave." Klaus Wildenhahn. Norddeutscher Rundfunk, Studio Hamburg., 1966; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate; B&W; 01:23:05
      - Edison College lecture, 2002 May 30; 0.08 Cubic Feet; 4 Video Recordings duplicates (Box 8, Object 29, Object 19, Reg number 210.V008.00, Object 20, Object 21)
      - "Merce Cunningham." Jackie Raynal., 1962; Cunningham, Merce; Cage, John; Raynal, Jackie, 1940-; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings 1 analog video recording and 1 digital surrogate; B&W; 00:24:00 (Box 8, Object 28, Reg number 64.V004.01)
        Also commonly known as "Image et Technique."
        Cunningham, Merce; Cage, John
      - "Merce Cunningham." London Weekend Television/South Bank Show., 1980 February 27; 0.10 Cubic Feet; 5 Video Recordings 2 analog window burn duplicates, 1 digital window burn surrogate and 2 digital surrogates of broadcast recording; 00:53:34; 00:56:37; 00:02:51 (Box 37, Object 6, Reg number 85.V044.01, Object 7, Reg number 85.V044.02)
        Digital objects include excerpted "Travelogue" performance.
      - "Merce Cunningham: A Lifetime of Dance." Charles Atlas., 1999; Atlas, Charles; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate; 01:30:38
        Cunningham, Merce
      - "The Collaborators." Angela Davis. KETC Public Television., 1986; Cunningham, Merce; Cage, John; Caplan, Elliot; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate of broadcast video recording; 00:56:04
        "Coast Zone" film is included at the end of "The Collaborators."
        Cunningham, Merce; Cage, John; Caplan, Elliot
    - "Antic Meet"
      - "Antic Meet." Sveriges Radio Televisionen., 1964; Arnbom, Arne; Cage, John; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate of broadcast video recording; B&W; 00:27:09
        Brown, Carolyn, 1927-; Cunningham, Merce; Farber, Viola; Paxton, Steve; Tudor, David, 1926-1996
    - "Changing Steps"
      - Cunningham Dance Foundation tape, 1989; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings duplicate (Box 8, Object 11)
    - "Event for Television"
      - "Merce Cunningham." Dance in America. WNET., 1976 November 14; 1977 January 5; 0.12 Cubic Feet; 5 Video Recordings 1 analog NTSC master, 2 analog duplicates and 2 digital surrogate excerpts; 00:00:44 (Box 8, Object 8, Reg number 76.V002.02, Box 37, Object 9, Object 12, Reg number 77.V002.00)
        Digital objects are excerpts of "Minutiae" performance.
    - "Interscape"
      - 'New piece' rehearsal footage, 2000 February 8; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings raw footage; duplicate (Box 8, Object 1, Reg number 200.V005.00)
    - "Night Wandering"
      - "Night Wandering (Nattvandrare)." Finnish Broadcasting Company., 1964; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate; B&W; 00:18:48
        Cunningham, Merce; Brown, Carolyn, 1927-
    - "Story"
      - Film transfer, circa 1963; 0.05 Cubic Feet; 0.02 Video Recordings film transfer duplicate (Box 37, Object 13, Reg number 85.V047.00)
    - Compilation
      - "Antic Meet," "Crises," "Night Wandering", 1961, 1964, 1976; 0.05 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings NTSC master (Box 8, Object 10, Reg number 76.V002.01)
  - [Dunn, Judith?], Dunn, Judith
    Dunn, Judith
    - "Acapulco"
      - Jill [Johnston?] interview, "Every 2 min something else", 1966 August 4; 0.016 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings acetate audio tape; 7.5 ips; mono 1/4 inch (Box 35, Object 5)
        General
        Text on physical reel is "Acapulco jill interview every two minutes something else." Jill Johnston wrote a big piece in the Voice about Judith Dunn around this time.
        Non-public note
        Contact Clare Croft chcroft@umich.edu if ever digitized.
  - Fahlström, Öyvind, Fahlström, Öyvind, 1928-1976
    - "Kisses Sweeter Than Wine"
      - "9 Evenings: Theater and Engineering: Öyvind Fahlström: Kisses Sweeter than Wine", 1966, 1996; 0.06 Cubic Feet; 4 Video Recordings 3 analog duplicates of titles, rough cut, screening copy and 1 digital surrogate; 00:17:44 (Box 8, Object 2, Reg number 66.V005.01, Object 3, Reg number 66.V005.02, Object 4, Reg number 66.V005.00)
  - Farber, Viola
    - "Brazos River"
      - "Brazos River." Fort Worth Art Museum., 1977; Farber, Viola; Tudor, David, 1926-1996; Lucier, Alvin; 0.001 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings digital surrogates; duplicates of broadcast video recording; 00:59:12 (Box 30, Object 27, Reg number 77.V003.00)
        Tudor, David, 1926-1996; Lucier, Alvin
  - First New York Theater Rally
    - Compilations
      - "Leadville," "Map Room II," "Pelican," "They Will," " Victory 14", circa 1965; Hay, Deborah; Hay, Alex; 0.17 Cubic Feet; 12 Video Recordings 1 analog film transfer master, 6 excerpted and full duplicates and 5 digital surrogates; 00:13:08; 00:13:08; 00:06:42; 00:06:42; 00:17:26 (Box 8, Object 5, Object 6, Object 7, Reg number 91.V031.00, Object 8, Reg number 63.V002.03, Object 9, Reg number data_value_missing_f06ad33ca31b3211af9b567e2c55be01, Box 37, Reg number 91.V028.00, Object 12)
        The recordings include various excerpts of Robert Rauschenberg's "Pelican" and "Map Room II," Alex Hay's "Leadville," and Deborah Hay's "They Will" (originally "Would They Wouldn't They,") and "Victory 14."
        Brown, Trisha, 1936-
  - Hay, Alex
    - "Leadville"
      - Film transfer, circa 1965; Hay, Alex; 0.04 Cubic Feet; 2 Video Recordings analog [film transfer] and duplicate (Box 8, Object 10, Object 11)
  - NOW Festival
    - "Remembering NOW", 2004 October 19; Denney, Alice; 0.02 Cubic Feet; 1 Video Recordings documentary; distribution copy (Box 8, Object 12, Reg number 204.V001.02)
      Denney, Alice
  - Paxton, Steve
    - "A.A."
      - Sound recording, circa 1966; 0.008 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings acetate audio tape; 7.5 ips; mono 1/4 inch (Box 35, Object 27)
    - "Section [of a New Unfinished Work: Augmented]" ?
      - Section: Steve (Mahler), circa 1966; 0.008 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings acetate audio tape; leadered sections 1/4 inch (Box 35, Object 28)
  - Rainer, Yvonne, Rainer, Yvonne, 1934-
    - "Parts of Some Sextets"
      - Sound recording, circa 1965; 0.016 Cubic Feet; 2 Sound Recordings acetate audio tape 1/4 inch (Box 35, Object 6, Object 29)
        One box is also labeled "Mystery (Aion) (Gnonthic)".
  - Rauschenberg, Robert
    - "Canoe" possibly used for a "Linoleum" rehearsal and performance, unidentified, 1976 October 5; 0.5 Cubic Feet; 4 Motion Picture Films B&W; positive; optical sound track; film transfers 16 mm; 1 Video Recordings digital betacam transfer (Box 45, Object 4, Reg number 76.MM003.00, Box 59, Object 1, Object 2, Object 3, Box 8, Object 11)
    - "Linoleum"
      - Performance footage. WNET - New York., circa 1966; 0.31 Cubic Feet; 14 Video Recordings broadcast recordings; 12 analog film transfers and video duplicates; 2 digital surrogates; masters and excerpts; NTSC and PAL; 00:14:21; 00:13:40; 0.29 Cubic Feet; 2 Motion Picture Films B&W; positive; optical sound track; metal reel 16 mm (Box 8, Object 13, Reg number 66.V004.01, Object 14, Reg number 99.V003.03, Object 15, Object 16, Object 17, Reg number 99.V003.01, Object 18, Box 37, Object 19, Reg number 66.V011.01, Object 20, Object 25, Box 30, Object 28, Object 10, Reg number 66.V004.00, Reg number 99.V003.05, Box 44, Object 4, Reg number 66.MM001.00, Object 5, Reg number 66.MM001.01)
    - "Open Score"
      - "9 Evenings: Theatre & Engineering: ROBERT RAUSCHENBERG: Open Score", 1966, 1996-1997; 0.08 Cubic Feet; 6 Video Recordings 4 analog copies of rough and final cuts; 2 digital surrogates; 00:42:33; 00:10:43 (Box 8, Object 1, Reg number 66.V008.06, Object 2, Reg number 66.V007.00, Object 3, Reg number 97.V027.00, Object 7, Reg number 66.V006.00)
    - "Pelican"
      - Judson Dance Theater excerpts, 1963 May; 1 Video Recordings digital surrogate of B&W 16 mm film; 00:02:20
        Brown, Carolyn, 1927-; Ultvedt, Per Olof, 1927-
      - Sound track, 1963; 0.016 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings acetate audio tape; 3.75 ips 1/4 inch (Box 35, Object 30, Reg number 63.A001.00)
    - "Performance" [Beer Bottle Band]
      - Performance and discussion, 1973; 0.001 Cubic Feet; 1 Sound Recordings interfiled log and transcript digital access copy (Box 30, Object 29)
    - "Shot Put"